Guide to the Daisy Aldan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 2000 Acquisition, 1940-1989; Series XIX; 50; (64 boxes) + 4 broadside folders, 5 art objects
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Sound recordings
      - Reel-to-reel tapes
        - Poems from "The Destruction of Cathedrals" and other poems by Daisy Aldan, 1962; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393166)
        - "Un Coup De Dés", Nin and Aldan, undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393174)
        - "Un Coup De Dés", Anais Nin and Daisy Aldan, 1960 ? October; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393182)
        - "Sound in Poetry", a lecture and reading by Daisy Aldan, 1962 May 3; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393190)
        - Gertrude Stein reads "The Making of Americans", Pt. 1 and 2 / "A Vlentine to Sherwood Anderson" / "If I Told Him: A Completed Portrait of Picasso, Matisse" / Madame Recamier: An Opera / A Ginsberg: Cottage in Berkeley, etc., undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393216)
        - Daisy Aldan, Reel I, 1972 December 10; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393208)
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393224)
        - Taz, undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393232)
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393240)
        - Daidy Aldan, Surrealism American poets, Anais, undated; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393257)
        - Daisy Aldan and Anais Nin, poems and translations, 1960 October; 1 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002091393265)
        - My 3 Songs, 1964; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509022)
        - Un Coup de dés, de Stéphane Mallarmé, 1960 November 23; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509030)
          conférenca illustée - lecture du poème en français, et en traduction anglaise
        - Scenes from Shakespeare on the Theme of the Consciousness Soul: A Search for the Higher Self, Part I, 1975 February 9; 1; 7 1/2 speed; dub (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509048)
        - Daisy Aldan Poems, undated; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509055)
        - Mrs Brenner's Luncheon, 1964; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509063)
          A note included with the audiotape reel reads: Daisy, Play and enjoy. Ray De.
        - Folder I, poems, 1993; 1 (Box 103, Item barcode 39002104509071)
        - Steffen Poems read by Daisy Alden, Marlis Schwieger, 1969 May 1; 1; 00:32:33; A hum can be heard on the tape. (Box 104, Item barcode 39002104509089)
        - Wind, Witches, Cinderella, Bremen Players, etc., undated; 1; 00:41:34; A hum can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 104, Item barcode 39002104509097)
        - Breakthrough with echo effect, undated; 1; 00:35:55; The program is distorted at times. The program is in silence from about 9:24 until 29:24. (Box 104, Item barcode 39002104509105)
          Restricted fragile materials.
        - The Innovators, 1963 January 14; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002104508990)
          7 1/2 speed; master audiotape reel
        - Scenes from Shakespeare on the Theme of the Consciousness Soul: A Search for the Higher Self, with commentary, 1975 February 9; 1; Master copy (Box 105, Item barcode 39002104509006)
        - Daisy Aldan on Great Jones St., excerpts, undated; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002104509014)
          A theatrical celelebration of the poetry of Daisy Aldan as presented by the Moving Theatre Co.
        - Empty Reel ?, undated; 1 (Box 105, Item barcode 39002104509287)
      - Audiocassettes
        Boxes 106-108, 110: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - Poetry reading, Daisy Aldan & M C Richards, 1976 July 22; 1; 01:00:46; The program is recorded at a very low level. High background noise can be heard on tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509303)
        - Anais Nin Tribute, Los Angeles, 1977 February 21; 1; 01:31:23; A warble can be heard at the top of the program. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509311)
        - Dennis Barrone interviews Daisy Aldan about Folder magazine, 1977 February 8; 1; 01:10:49; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509337)
        - Women's Salon Tribute to Anais Nin, 1976; 1; 01:18:53; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509345)
        - Shakespeare Construction Co., Aldan, Tazwell copy, 1975 December 6; 1; 01:09:43; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509352)
        - Karoline Von Günderrode Part II, undated; 1; 00:54:50; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509360)
          A note with the audiocassette states the tape is no good.
        - Miss McIntosh till 366, Chapter 28-29 (parts of), May 24-25; 1; The program is distorted at times. High frequency noise can be heard at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509329)
        - The Mission of the Poet, Spring Valley, 1976 October 27; 1; 00:44:49; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509378)
        - Gregorian Chants / Socrates, undated; 1; 01:32:22; Static and a high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509386)
        - Marian Seldeco reading "Chapter 2" about the Opium Lady, 1975 January 12; 1; 01:03:33; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard. There is a recorded silence from 39:47 to 54:45. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509394)
        - Miss McIntosh, undated; 1; 01:01:29; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509402)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 01:30:47; The program is distorted at times. High background noise and static can be heard. A high amount of hum is on the tape. Warbling can be heard near the end of the program. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509410)
        - [?], 1976; 1; 00:16:10; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509428)
        - In Recording Diana Cohen, 1976 March 30; 1; 01:01:56; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509436)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 01:30:47; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509444)
        - Inge Mo[?], German translation, 1976 February 4; 1; 00:22:02; High background noise and static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509451)
        - "The Little Sparrow", Edith Piaf / "I Regret Nothing", 1976 March 18; 1; 01:02:16; The program is distorted at times. High background noise and static can be heard. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509469)
          There is a handwritten poem and note, dated 1976-04-10, included with the audiocassette that reads: Away then, I am lock'd in one of them, If you do love me, you will find me out. Nerissa and the rest, stand all aloof, let music sound while he doth make his choice, then if he lose, he makes a swanlike end, fading in music. Mer V: Portia, III, 2, 44. And watch the fleeting white clouds of spring, they, sometimes do deceive. For Easter and Passover, Deepest love, Diana Cohen
          Channel 13 - film mag.; narrator: Louis Jordan.
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:47:09; High background noise and a high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509477)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:10:37; Static can be heard on the tape. The recording is muffled. The program is recorded at a very low level. The program is distorted at times. (Box 106, Item barcode 39002104509485)
        - Daisy's Day at Rudolf Steiner Inst. III, "Shakespeare and the Conscience Soul" / Poetry Reading and Dr. Schmidt's, 1976 July 28-30; 1; 01:48:52; High background noise can be heard in the first 48 minutes of the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392309)
        - Erica Duncan "Anais Nin", 1976 June 30; 1; 01:02:23; High background noise and static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392317)
        - Daisy Aldan on Mallarmé with John Beck, 1998 December 12; 1; 01:38:24 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392325)
          Dolby B
        - Aviva Espiedra, Mendelssohn/Chopin, 1984 July 16; 1; 00:51:29 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392333)
          Baltimore Chamber Festival
        - Daisy Aldan on Mallarmé with John Beck, 1998 December 12; 1; 01:39:32 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392341)
          Anthroposophical Society, NYC
        - Stravinsky "The Dove Descending", undated; 1; 01:19:28; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392358)
          Scenes 1-11
        - Troubadour Montse[?], undated; 1; 00:51:34; Clicks, pops, and static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392366)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:11:44; A high amount of hiss and background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392374)
          A note found with the audiocassette reads: Daisy - CML tape enjoy - turn volume up! - Pst
        - Janet Baker singing Shumer Scarletti and Monte Verdi, undated; 1; 01:31:57; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392382)
        - Jeremy Storch "Testimony", presented at Temple Aron Kodesh, 1987 August 2; 1; 00:57:28; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392390)
        - Selected Poems, Joanna Neilan, undated; 1; 01:00:03; The program is distorted at times for the first 47 minutes of the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392408)
        - Daisy Aldan reads Mallarmé, 1998 December 18; 1; 00:34:51 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392416)
          Total Time: 35:05
        - Kustermann Kiss, undated; 1; Deterioration of the audiocassette due to sticky-shed syndrome has made the tape unusable. It has not been digitized. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392424)
        - "Calisto" by Cavalli, Tape I, undated; 1; 01:34:32; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. The audio is distorted for a few minutes beginning at 00:47:15. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392432)
        - Daisy Aldan Reads Mallarmé, 1999; 1; 00:35:01; An audible echo can be heard on the audiocassette. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392440)
          Contents are listed below.
          Side 1 / Side 2
          Apparition
          Soupir
          L'Azur
          Rondell II
          Autre Éventail
          Les Fleurs
          Le Tombeau d'Edgar Poe
          Aumône
          Renouveau
          Las de l'amer repos
          Le Pitre Chatié
          Cantique de St. Jean
          Remémoration
          Quand l'ombre
          Mes bouquins refermés
          Salut
        - Jeremy "Let Every Knee", 1985; 1; 00:36:04; Static, clicks, and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392457)
          A list of contents are included below.
          Let Every Knee
          Give Your Heart to Jesus
          Take Me Back
          I Am
          Dance Jerusalem
          Hebrew Lord
          Bread of Life
          The Rider
          White Horse
        - Schubert Trio No. 2 in E flat Major / Mossy, undated; 1; 01:31:03; Clicks, pops, and static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392465)
        - Concerts et Danses De La Renaissance Daus Les Cours d Europe, undated; 1; 01:33:05; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392473)
        - Poetry and Prose for Friends by Steve Spangler Part I, 1987 Spring; 1; 01:19:49; High background noise can be be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392481)
        - Spring - Easter Part II, 1987; 1; 01:27:41; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392499)
        - Spring - Easter Part IV, 1987; 1; 01:20:50; Static and high background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392507)
        - To Daisy from Winn Chanin, undated; 1; 01:33:44; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392515)
        - Cuperin Clavean and Bach French Suites on Chimbaloms, undated; 1; 01:30:15; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392523)
        - Brahms & Ravel / Wagner, undated; 1; 01:31:47; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392531)
        - Sea Pictures: Elgar / Des Knaben Wunderhorn Mahler / Ariodante aria - Handel / Bach arias / Janet Baker sings, 1981 January 25; 1; 01:34:10; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392549)
        - Hougness-Whales-Williams / Vaughn Williams, undated; 1; 01:33:41; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392556)
        - Calisto Tape II and Arie Amorose, Janet Baker, undated; 1; 01:34:19; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. There is phasing or timing issues on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392564)
        - Debussy Images I and II / Children's Corner, Michel Angeli, undated; 1; 01:28:57; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392572)
        - Ancient Greek Music, Tarentelle, undated; 1; 01:34:11; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392580)
        - Reader's Almanac, Walter James Miller, 1978 July 24; 1; 00:27:04; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392598)
          WNYC-FM
        - Mendelssohn: Die Erste Walpurgisnacht / Giestliche Chorwerhe / Hungarian Gregorian chants, undated; 1; 01:34:33; Clicks, pops, and static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392606)
        - Rudolf Steiner: 12 Harmonies, Verses for the Zodiac, translation and commentary by Daisy Aldan, 1999 April 3; 1; 01:07:39; High background noise can be heard on the tape. High frequency background noise can be heard as well. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392614)
        - Abbess, Hildegard at Bin[?]en / Wolf, Penthesilea, undated; 1; 01:34:02; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392622)
        - Whales, Basel, Whitman / Little Mermaid (?), undated; 1; 00:41:34 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392630)
        - Brahms / Debussy /Britten / Wagner, Tape III, undated; 1; 01:34:21; Static can be heard on the tape. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392648)
        - Anais Nin film interview by Daisy Aldan, 1963; 1; 01:04:05; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distored at times. There is low-level crosstalk that can be heard at about 32:10. Silence recorded on the tape from about 15:59 to 16:46. (Box 107, Item barcode 39002091392655)
        - Diana Cohen, 1976 April 26; 1; 00:42:32; The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509493)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:31:06; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509501)
        - Spring-Easter, Part II, 1987; 1; 01:28:46; High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509519)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509527)
        - Melos Quartet with Enrique Santiago, Voila II (Box 108)
          This appears to be a commercial tape.
        - New Wine Live at Temple Aron Kodesh, undated; 1; 00:43:28 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509535)
          The audiocassette is recorded in stereo. Contents are listed below.
          New Wine Will Run from the Mountains
          Shalom Shalom
          King of Glory
          Behold the Lamb of God
          They Will Look Upon Me
          Hallelujah Yeshua
          Soldiers of the Light
          The Power of his Blood
          There's Going to be a Revival
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509543)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509550)
        - Yo[?] side, undated; 1; 00:16:16; Static can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. Thumping and tweet sounds can be heard on the program. The program ends abruptly. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509568)
          A note with this audiocassette reads: Take home [?][?]
        - All Crammed In, 1992 October 10; 1; 02:03:56; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. Phasing or time differences in the sound can be heard on the program. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509576)
          The audiocassette is a mix tape of various music.
        - Untitled, Undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509584)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:00:10; The program is very short. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509592)
          There is a note on the cover of this audiocassette that reads: This is my 1st tape. Another note also reads: push button when you start comm[?].
        - English Lesson I, undated; 1; 00:32:12; A high amount of background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509600)
        - Trois Poèmes de Stéphane Mallarmé, Maurice Rave, undated; 1; 00:12:23 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509618)
          singer: Anne Sofie Von Otter, piano: Bengt Foriberg
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509626)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509634)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509642)
        - Abby?, undated; 1; 00:49:56; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509659)
        - Poetry on Prayer, performed by Tamir, 1990; 1; 00:35:40 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509667)
          There is a list of contents included.
          Side A / Side B
          Equality
          Prayer
          Inability to Pray
          Pain
          Where's Prayer
          Hope
          Asking
          Peace
          Love
          Birth
          Veils
          The Answer
        - Alicia Ghiragossian Reads Her Poems, 1987; 1; 00:12:59; Static can be heard at the end of the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509675)
        - The Oracle, begins at no. 017, undated; 1; 00:00:33; High frequency interference can be heard on the tape. High background noise can also be heard. The program is very distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509683)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509691)
        - Paradise Play Goetheanum, 1975 December 24; 1; 01:58:23; A high amount of background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509709)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509717)
        - Sylvia Plath Anyone for Tennyson?, 1976 April 26; 1; 00:27:42; A high amount of background noise and buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509725)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:00:18; The program is not very long. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509733)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:53:09 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509741)
          On the cassette, Daisy Aldan is heard interviewing a man regarding Rudolf Steiner.
        - Chant Grégorian / Verteidigrungsrede des Sokrates gerproclieu vou Werner Krauss, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509758)
        - Whistler and His Dog / Sound of Jetplane / SL "C-11" Oigawa Railway / Los Enamordos, undated; 1; 00:08:18 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509766)
          stereo
        - Francois Couperin Pieces de Clavecin, Vol. I, undated; 1; 01:30:10; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509774)
        - Untitled, undated; 1; This audiocassette is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509782)
        - Outgoing message tape, undated; 1; 00:00:32; The program is very distorted at times. A high amount of hum can be heard on the tape. There is tone on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509790)
          30-second endless loop
        - Shakespeare Munz, nothing, undated; 1; 00:11:47; The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509808)
        - Gertrude Stein reads from her works, undated; 1; 00:19:06; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509816)
          A list of contents is included.
          Side A
          "The Making of Americans", Parts 1 and 2
          "A Valentine to Sherwood Anderson
          "Portrait of Picasso / Matisse"
          "Madame Recamier", an opera
        - Gustav Holst / Savitri / Chopin Preludes, tape IV, undated; 1; 01:33:20; Clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104509824)
        - Head demagnetizer, undated (Box 108)
        - Lesson I: Creative Teaching of English (empty case), 1976 (Box 108)
        - Sinatra + Felicia Sanders (empty case), undated (Box 108)
        - Concerts et Danses de la Renaissance Dans Les Cours, D Europe (empty case), undated (Box 108)
        - Black Box 16 (1 of 2 cassettes), 1978; 1; 00:59:14; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard. (Box 110, Item barcode 39002091392283)
          The two audiocassettes came with the Black Box 16 container.
        - Black Box 16 (2 of 2 cassettes), 1978; 1; 00:58:36 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002091392291)
      - Sound discs
        Box 97 and 109: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - Various readings and radio programs (28 10" and 1 7") (Box 109 (Record Album Storage))
        - Unidentified 7" (Box 97)
    - Video recordings
      Box 110: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Daisy Aldan, One Woman Show", undated; YCALMSS613_0004; 1; 01:40:41 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002102300333)
      - Unidentified, undated; YCALMSS613_0005; 1; 00:52:56 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002102300341)
      - Unidentified, undated; YCALMSS613_0006; 1; 01:58:30 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002102300358)
      - "Daisy Aldan", 1982 May 21; YCALMSS613_0007; 1; 00:30:37 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002102300366)
      - "Geronimo Sands Shakespeare Program", 1990 [February 5]; YCALMSS613_0008; 1; 00:57:35 (Box 110, Item barcode 39002102300374)
  - Oversize
    - Aldan, Daisy. In Passage, proofs, 5 (Box 111 (Oversize))
    - Unidentified text and illustration pasteups (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Unidentified proofs (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Paroles Peintes, proofs (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Paroles Peintes, printed version (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Black Sun Press Portfolio, printed version (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Poster for Anaïs Nin lecture (Box 112 (Oversize))
    - Unidentified layout transparencies (Box 113(Broadside))
      Box 113 (Broadside): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
- June 2005 Acquisition, circa 1940-1980; Series XX; 1.63; (3 boxes)